Slavery was not genocide.
Oh, hold on, excuse me.
Can I just read something for you real quick there?
Just give me one sec.
The floor of their room, so covered with blood and mucus
that it resembled a slaughterhouse
by Alexander Falconbridge, a slave ship doctor.
Anyways, sorry, go ahead, sir.
Otherwise, there wouldn't be so many damn blacks in Africa
or in Britain, would there?
You know, an awful lot of them survived.
Oh, so the estimated 1.8 to 2 million Africans
who died just on the Middle Passage alone
does not account for a genocide.
Ah, okay, please, go ahead, go ahead.
The honest teaching of the British Empire
is to say, quite simply, it is the first key stage
of world globalization.
It's probably the most important moment in human history,
and it is still with us.
Its consequences are still on, and generally speaking,
in most ways, actually fruitful.
Yes, you are right, you are so right,
because Simon Fraser, an enslaver of over 1,000 people,
who received about 10 million pounds in compensation.
And so did John Gladstone, who is the father
of the British Prime Minister, Edward Gladstone,
who received about 12 to 13 million pounds,
the biggest payout in history.
But no, go ahead, go ahead.
No, it's okay, sorry, go ahead.
And as for the idea, as I said,
that slavery is this kind of terrible disease
that dare not speak its name,
it only dare not speak its name, Darren,
because we settled it nearly 200 years ago.
Yes, you are right.
It was settled.
It was settled by paying off the enslavers
billions of pounds in today's money.
So in order to end slavery, the deal was to pay the enslavers
and not the enslavers.
Ah, okay, you know, ah, yeah, yes, you know.
We don't normally go on about the fact that Roman Catholics,
once upon a time, didn't have vote and weren't allowed to have their own churches
because we have Catholic emancipation.
And do you know what?
We had Catholic emancipation at pretty much exactly the same time
that we got rid of slavery in the 1830s.
We don't fall on the back.
Yes, we must move on, right?
The same enslaved people and their descendants
who were forced under oppressive colonial laws
to stay within the plantation system
and under the helm of colonialism.
Yeah, you're right, we must move on.